Guide to the Howard Zinn Papers TAM.542
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archive
- Series V: Boston University, 1960-2003
  - Subseries V:B: Boston University Controversy, 1962-2002
    - American Association of University Professors (AAUP) Materials, 1983-1985, undated (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Anti-War (Vietnam), 1968-1973 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Anti-War (Vietnam): Police Action March 27, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Banner Hanging Dispute: Abramowitz, Yosef I. et al. v. Trustees of Boston University, 1986 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Bias against Zinn, [1974]-1980, undated (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1965-1970 (Box 22, Folder 17)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1972-1979 (Box 22, Folder 18)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1980-1981 (Box 22, Folder 19)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1982 (Box 22, Folder 20)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1983 (Box 22, Folder 21)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1985 (Box 22, Folder 22)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1986-1989 (Box 22, Folder 23)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1990-1996 (Box 22, Folder 24)
    - Boston University Controversy, 1991-2002, undated (Box 22, Folder 25)
    - Boston University Labor Council (BULC), 1979-1980, undated (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Budget / Financial Issues, 1976-1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Budget / Financial Issues, 1976-1986, undated (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Building and Grounds Workers (SEIU, Local 254), 1977-1979 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - Building and Grounds Workers (SEIU, Local 254): Strike, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - Building and Grounds Workers (SEIU, Local 254): Strike - Press, 1978 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Campus Media: the bu exposure, 1977-1984, undated (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Campus Media: the bu exposure - Articles from the bu exposure and Daily Free Press, 1977-1983 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Campus Media: the bu exposure - the bu exposure Collective v. John Silber, et al., 1978-1983 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Campus Media: the bu exposure - the bu exposure Collective v. John Silber, et al. - Silber Deposition, 1982 (Box 23, Folder 10)
    - Campus Media: WBUR, 1977-1978, 1986 (Box 23, Folder 11)
    - Central Intelligence Agency, 1974-1987 (Box 23, Folder 12)
    - Chronology of Daily Free Press Items, [1985] (Box 23, Folder 13)
    - Civil Liberties - Clippings, 1972-1986 (Box 23, Folder 14)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts (CLUM) Inquiry and Report, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 15)
    - Civil Liberties Union of Massachusetts (CLUM) Inquiry and Report - Related Material, 1976-1980, undated (Box 23, Folder 16)
    - Committee to Save Boston University, 1973-1980, undated (Box 23, Folder 17)
    - Committee to Save Boston University, 1974-1980 (Box 23, Folder 18)
    - Committee to Save Boston University, 1979-1980 (Box 23, Folder 19)
    - Committee to Save Boston University, 1979-1980, undated (Box 23, Folder 20)
    - Committee to Save Boston University, 1980, undated (Box 23, Folder 21)
    - Committee to Save Boston University: Lists and Related Materials, 1979, undated (Box 23, Folder 22)
    - Committee to Save Boston University: State Senator Gerard D'Amico, 1980 (Box 23, Folder 23)
    - Department of Political Science, 1974-1975 (Box 23, Folder 24)
    - Diamandopoulos, Peter, 1997-1999 (Box 23, Folder 25)
    - Draft Registration and Financial Aid, 1983 (Box 23, Folder 26)
    - Draft Registration and Financial Aid: Doe, John and Paul Poe v. Trustees of BU and Silber (I), 1983 (Box 23, Folder 27)
    - Draft Registration and Financial Aid: Doe, John and Paul Poe v. Trustees of BU and Silber (II), 1983 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Faculty Council Opposition to Duarte Honorary Degree (and Silber response), 1986 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Faculty Tenure, Appointments, 1969-1987, undated (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Faculty Tenure, Appointments: Bottome, Edgar, 1970, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - Faculty Tenure, Appointments: Giroux, Henry, 1982-1983 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Lists, Various, 1980-1988, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Marcuse, Herbert (substitute for Zinn), 1974 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - "Mismanagement and Corruption", 1978-1990 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Newspapers: the bu exposure, 1977 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Newspapers: the bu exposure, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Newspapers: the bu exposure, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Newspapers: the bu exposure, 1980, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Newspapers: The Daily Free Press, 1972, 1977, 1978 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - Newspapers: The Daily Free Press, Jan 1979-Feb 1979 (Box 24, Folder 14)
    - Newspapers: The Daily Free Press, Mar 1979-Apr 1979 (Box 24, Folder 15)
    - Newspapers: The Daily Free Press, Oct 1979-Apr 1981 (Box 24, Folder 16)
    - Nursing School Closure, 1987 (Box 24, Folder 17)
    - Photograph (Howard Zinn, Frances Fox Piven, Murray Levin), 1977 (Box 85, Folder 5)
    - "Pursuing Excellence at Boston University" by Frances Piven, Murray Levin and Howard Zinn, 1975 (Box 24, Folder 18)
    - Redmont, Bernard S., 1985-1986 (Box 24, Folder 19)
    - "Report of the Boston University Faculty Council on Academic Freedom", 1996 (Box 24, Folder 20)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) and Military Recruitment, 1972 (Box 24, Folder 21)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) and Military Recruitment, 1972-1974, undated (Box 24, Folder 22)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) and Military Recruitment, 1973 (Box 24, Folder 23)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) and Military Recruitment, 1976, 1980, 1984 (Box 24, Folder 24)
    - Reserve Officer Training Corps (ROTC) and Military Recruitment, undated (Box 24, Folder 25)
    - Silber, John: Arson Accusation against Howard Zinn, 1972, 1979-1980 (Box 24, Folder 26)
    - Silber, John: Articles, Various, 1972-1979 (Box 24, Folder 27)
    - Silber, John: Articles, Various, 1972-1990, undated (Box 24, Folder 28)
    - Silber, John: Articles, Various, 1980-1987 (Box 24, Folder 29)
    - Silber, John: Articles, Various, 1993-1995, undated (Box 24, Folder 30)
    - Silber, John: Faculty Call for Removal of Silber, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - Silber, John: Faculty Call for Removal of Silber - Outside Support (alumni), 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Silber, John: Faculty Call for Removal of Silber - Outside Support (includes letter from Henry Steele Commager), 1979 (Box 25, Folder 3)
    - Silber, John: Letters, Letters to Editor re: Silber, 1976-1979, 1989-1999, undated (Box 25, Folder 4)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race, 1989-1990 (Box 25, Folder 5)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race - "Factbook on John Silber", 1990 (Box 25, Folder 6)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race - "Factbook on John Silber" - General, 1990 (Box 25, Folder 7)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race - "Factbook on John Silber" - Raw Materials (I), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 8)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race - "Factbook on John Silber" - Raw Materials (II), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 9)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race - "Factbook on John Silber" - Raw Materials (III), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 10)
    - Silber, John: Massachusetts Gubernatorial Race - Op-Ed Pieces by Howard Zinn (includes draft), 1990 (Box 25, Folder 11)
    - Silber, John: Transcript of Interview Concerning Howard Zinn (12/3/1979) (Box 25, Folder 12)
    - Silber, John: Writings (includes letter from Silber with Zinn annotations), 1974-1983, undated (Box 25, Folder 13)
    - South Africa, Anti-Apartheid Materials, 1985-1987, undated (Box 25, Folder 14)
    - Strike! Poster, 1970; Currently unavailable - awaiting preservation treatment (Flat-file 1, Drawer 2)
    - Strikes: 1979, 1978-1979 (Box 25, Folder 15)
    - Strikes: 1979 (I) (Box 25, Folder 16)
    - Strikes: 1979 (II) (Box 25, Folder 17)
    - Strikes: 1979 (III) (Box 25, Folder 18)
    - Strikes: 1979 (IV) (Box 25, Folder 19)
    - Strikes: 1979, 1979, undated (Box 25, Folder 20)
    - Strikes: 1979 - Legal, 1979-1980 (Box 25, Folder 21)
    - Strikes: Negatives, undated (Box 25, Folder 22)
    - Student Demonstration against General Electric Recruiters and Aftermath (11/25/1969), 1969-1970 (Box 25, Folder 23)
    - Student, Faculty Code Issues, 1970-1986 (Box 25, Folder 24)
    - Student Health Center (includes National Labor Relations Board Discrimination Case), 1975-1978, undated (Box 26, Folder 1)
    - Student Paper: "John Silber and the BU Crisis: The Faculty Strike of 1979" by Claudia Krakowski (Box 26, Folder 2)
    - Student Strike, 1970 (Box 26, Folder 3)
    - Teach-In February 14, 1979 (Box 26, Folder 4)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt, 1987, 1990 (Box 26, Folder 5)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 1), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 6)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 2), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 7)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 3), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 4), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 5), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 6), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 7), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 8), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 9), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 10), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 11), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 12), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Transcript (Day 13 - Closing Arguments and Charge), 1987 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Tenure Discrimination: Brown, Julia Prewitt v. Trustees of Boston University - Zinn Notes, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Trustees (I), 1974-1982 (Box 27, Folder 1)
    - Trustees (II), 1974-1982 (Box 27, Folder 2)
    - Trustees, 1976-1980, 1990, undated (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - Tuition Increases, 1978-1991, undated (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Vendors on Campus, 1976, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Women's Issues, 1970-1980 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Zinn Application for Metcalf Award, 1988 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Zinn Correspondence with Herman Frederick Eilts (various topics), 1983-1986 (Box 27, Folder 8)
    - Zinn Pay Docking Grievance, 1979-1980 (Box 27, Folder 9)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances, 1974-1978 (Box 27, Folder 10)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances, 1979 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances (I), 1980 (Box 27, Folder 12)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances (II), 1980 (Box 27, Folder 13)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances, 1981 (Box 27, Folder 14)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances, 1982-1983 (Box 27, Folder 15)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances, 1984-1985 (Box 27, Folder 16)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances, 1987 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances: Summaries and Emily Dalgarno (AAUP) Package, 1979-1981 (Box 27, Folder 18)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances: Supporting Material, 1962-1981, undated (Box 27, Folder 19)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances: Supporting Material - Evaluations, 1969-1981 (Box 27, Folder 20)
    - Zinn Salary, Merit Grievances: Supporting Material - Evaluations, 1979-1983 (Box 27, Folder 21)
    - Zinn Sit-In Participation, December 8, 1969, 1970 (Box 27, Folder 22)
- Series VI: Race and Civil Rights, 1932-2008
  This series contains material reflecting Howard Zinn’s involvement in the struggle for civil rights including articles and special reports written by Zinn; documents from the Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), an organization for which he was an advisor; transcripts of interviews he conducted, including one with Stokely Carmichael; many clippings, court documents and publications. In addition, there is a good deal of research material on race, slavery, reconstruction and the civil rights movement.
  - Abolitionism: Slavery and the Ante-Bellum South, 1953-1966, undated (Box 27, Folder 23)
  - "Abolitionist": Article Reviewing Books by Staughton Lynd (with Zinn annotations), 1968 (Box 27, Folder 24)
  - Abolitionists: Black, White (and other white reactions), 1951, 1964, undated (Box 27, Folder 25)
  - Abolitionists: Lecture Materials, 1962-1968, undated (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Acts of Violence (includes WATS Reports from SNCC and COFO), 1959-1977, undated (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Affirmative Action, 1966, 1988, 1994-1995, undated (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - African Studies in America - The Extended Family - A Tribal Analysis of U.S. Africanists: Who They Are; Why to Fight Them, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Albany, Georgia: Charles Sherrod / SNCC, 1961-1964, undated (Box 28, Folder 5)
  - Albany, Georgia: Reports Written by Howard Zinn for the Southern Regional Council, 1962, 1963 (Box 28, Folder 6)
  - Articles Based on "The Federal Civil Rights Enforcement Effort" (U.S. Commission on Civil Rights), 1970 (Box 28, Folder 7)
  - Atlanta (notes), 1960, undated (Box 28, Folder 8)
  - Atlanta: 30th Anniversary, The Atlanta University Center Civil Rights Movement (includes Certificate of Merit, Zinn, signed by Maynard Jackson), 1990 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Birmingham (articles), 1963, 2001 (Box 28, Folder 10)
  - Black Chronicle, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 11)
  - Black Justice, 1965-1970 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Black Justice, 1971-1978, undated (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Black Movement, 1960s, 1977, 1988-1989, undated (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Black Nationalism, 1966, 1968, 1983, undated (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - "Black People and the Tyranny of American Law" by Haywood Burns, undated (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - "Brown at 50: King's Dream or Plessy's Nightmare?" by Gary Oldfield and Chungmei Lee, 2004 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Civil Rights Act of 1964, 1963-1965 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Civil War Issues, 1963-1975, undated (Box 28, Folder 19)
  - DuBois, W.E.B.: Writing Annotated by Zinn and Biographical Article, undated (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - Early Twentieth Century: Federal Government and the Negro, 1960, undated (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - Federal Involvement, 1963-1967 (Box 28, Folder 22)
  - Federal Involvement, 1963-1969, undated (Box 28, Folder 23)
  - Federal Involvement, undated (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - Georgia Justice, 1959, 1962, undated (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - Goodman (Andrew), Schwerner (Michael) and Chaney (James Earl), 1964, 1988-1989 (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - Hampton, Fred, 1970-1976, undated (Box 28, Folder 27)
  - Hampton, Fred (includes copies of FBI documents and COINTELPRO materials), 1974-1977 (Box 28, Folder 28)
  - Hampton, Fred: Court Documents (copies), 1975-1976 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Hampton, Fred: Newspaper Clippings (copies), 1974-1976 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - In Memphis: More than a Garbage Strike by J. Edwin Stanfield, 1968 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Johnson and Civil Rights, 1958-1962 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Johnson and Civil Rights, 1963-1973, undated (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Justice in the American South by Anthony Lester (pamphlet published by Amnesty International/UK), [1964] (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Kennedy and Civil Rights, 1960-1965,1984, undated (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - King, Martin Luther Jr.: Race and Class, 1965-2007, undated (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Law and Negro Rights 1960-1964, 1961-1967, undated (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Mississippi (includes clippings re: James H. Meredith, enrollment at University of Mississippi), 1962-1964 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Mississippi: City of Hattiesburg v. Robert Moses - Hearing Transcript, Jan 23, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Mississippi Freedom Schools, 1992-2001 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Mississippi Summer, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 13)
  - Mississippi Summer: Clippings, 1964 (Box 29, Folder 14)
  - Mississippi Summer: "Project Volunteers Twenty-fifth Anniversary Reunion Journal", 1989 (Box 29, Folder 15)
  - Negro History, 1948-1981, undated (Box 29, Folder 16)
  - Negroes in American History: A Freedom Primer, 1965 (Box 29, Folder 17)
  - New Deal and the Negro, 1932-1973, undated (Box 29, Folder 18)
  - New South Volume 27 Number 4, 1972 (Box 29, Folder 19)
  - Notes and Draft: Zinn Review of The Victims of Democracy: Malcolm X and the Black Revolution by Eugene Victor Wolfenstein, [1982] (Box 29, Folder 20)
  - Post-Civil War Politics, 1954-1955, undated (Box 29, Folder 21)
  - Race, 1960-2008, undated (Box 29, Folder 22)
  - Race, 1961-2002, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Race, 1963-1983, undated (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Race, 1964-1995, undated (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Race, 1870-1900 ("Overthrowing Radical Reconstruction"), undated (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Race, 1945-1970, 1956-1969, undated (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Race - Notes, Drafts, Fragments, undated (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Race-based Intelligence Controversy, 1980, undated (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Racial Barriers in Sports, 1989, 1990, 1992 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Racism and the Death Penalty: James Victore Poster, 1993 (Flat-file 1, Drawer 2)
  - Reconstruction, 1950-1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Reconstruction: Blacks and Law, 1963-1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 10)
  - Reconstruction: Blacks and Law, 1965, undated (Box 30, Folder 11)
  - Reconstruction: Radical Reconstruction, 1965-1975, undated (Box 30, Folder 12)
  - "Robert F. Williams, 'Black Power,' and the Roots of the African American Struggle" by Timothy B. Tyson, 1998 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Scottsboro (notes), 1980, undated (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Slavery, 1968-1976, undated (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Slavery, 1985-1991, undated (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Slavery: Early Slavery, 1960-1976, undated (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Southern Exposure Volume 11, Numbers 2 and 3, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Speech Transcripts: Bob Moses and Bayard Rustin, 1963, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Strategies, Electoral, 1977, undated (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) Documents, 1962-1965 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC) Documents, 1966, undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Supreme Court, 1962-1989, undated (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Transparencies, undated (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Transparencies (includes Martin Luther King, Jr.), undated (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - "Trouble in Mind: The Bicentennial and the Afro-American Experience" by Leon F. Litwack, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Various Materials, 1950-2002, undated (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Voting Rights, 1950, 1962-1967, undated (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Voting Rights, 1960-1968, undated (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Zinn Interview Transcripts: Mrs. Mattie Pilcher and Stokely Carmichael, 1963 (Box 31, Folder 7)
- Series VII: Vietnam War, 1944-2001
  As with the series on Race and Civil Rights, this series contains background/research material on Southeast Asia and US involvement in Vietnam, as well as a great deal of material documenting Zinn’s own participation in the anti-war movement. Of particular interest are his travels to various anti-war conferences in Japan in 1966 and to Vietnam in 1968 and 1972, especially his Hanoi trip with Rev. Daniel Berrigan to receive prisoners released by the North Vietnamese. This is a large series with many articles, clippings, notebooks, photographs and publications. Materials extend through 2001 documenting post-war activities and influences.
  A smaller subseries contains items relating to the release of the Pentagon Papers and Zinn’s involvement with Daniel Ellsberg and Anthony Russo, including copies of court documents, hearing transcripts, and the Gravel Edition of The Pentagon Papers.
  - Subseries VII:A: Vietnam War Material, 1944-2001
    - "Absurdity" (notes, drafts, clippings), 1966, undated (Box 31, Folder 8)
    - "Accident or Structure", 1973-1990, undated (Box 31, Folder 9)
    - After the Cease Fire, 1972-1974 (Box 31, Folder 10)
    - Aggression, 1963-Apr 1966 (Box 31, Folder 11)
    - Aggression, Jun 1966-1967, undated (Box 31, Folder 12)
    - Air War, 1971 (Box 31, Folder 13)
    - Air War, 1972, undated (Box 31, Folder 14)
    - Air War: Articles by Fred Branfman, 1969-1972 (Box 31, Folder 15)
    - Air War: "Laos: Voices from Beneath the Earth, Recollections of Five Years under American Bombs", 1971 (Box 31, Folder 16)
    - Anti-War Ad Campaign, 1972 (Box 31, Folder 17)
    - "Atrocities in Vietnam: Myths and Realities" by Edward S. Herman, [1970] (Box 31, Folder 18)
    - Beyond Vietnam, 1959-1966 (Box 31, Folder 19)
    - Beyond Vietnam, 1967-1968, undated (Box 31, Folder 20)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, 1945-1961 (Box 31, Folder 21)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, 1962-1965 (Box 31, Folder 22)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, Jan 1971-Apr 1971 (Box 31, Folder 23)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, May 1971-Dec 1971 (Box 31, Folder 24)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, Jan 1972-May 1972 (Box 31, Folder 25)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, Jun 1972-Dec 1972 (Box 31, Folder 26)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, 1973-Mar 1975 (Box 32, Folder 1)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina, Apr 1975-1976, undated (Box 32, Folder 2)
    - Beyond Vietnam: Southeast Asia / Indochina: Indochina Today, 1973 (Box 32, Folder 3)
    - Cambodia, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 4)
    - Cambodia: Summer 1973 Bombing (clippings), 1973-1974 (Box 32, Folder 5)
    - Casualties, 1962-1969 (Box 32, Folder 6)
    - Casualties, 1970 (Box 32, Folder 7)
    - Casualties, 1971-1972, undated (Box 32, Folder 8)
    - Causes, Origins and Lessons of the Vietnam War: Hearings before the Senate Foreign Relations Committee, May 1972 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    - "The Columbia Eagle Affair" by Will Soper, 1974 (Box 32, Folder 10)
    - Corporations Producing Military Material: Dow Chemical Company, 1966-1968, undated (Box 32, Folder 11)
    - Corporations Producing Military Material: General Electric, 1972 (Box 32, Folder 12)
    - Corporations Producing Military Material: Honeywell, 1972-1973 (Box 32, Folder 13)
    - Corporations Producing Military Material: Raytheon, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence (includes letters from Zinn's 1968 Hanoi Trip), 1965-1975, 1987, undated (Box 32, Folder 15)
    - Course Outline: "A Study of Appropriate Technology: Reconstruction in Vietnam and Laos - Technological Alternatives and Political Implications", 1978 (Box 32, Folder 16)
    - Defoliation - Agent Orange, 1966-1970, 2000, undated (Box 32, Folder 17)
    - Diem (Ngo Dinh Diem), 1954, 1960-1964, undated (Box 32, Folder 18)
    - Drachman, Edward: Annotated Typescript and Notes from Drachman Book on U.S. Vietnam Policy 1941-1945, undated (Box 32, Folder 19)
    - Drachman, Edward: "The U.S. and Vietnam in 1945: A Lost Friendship", 1968 (Box 32, Folder 20)
    - Economics, 1965-1967, 1973, undated (Box 32, Folder 21)
    - Economics and Social Reform in Vietnam, 1966-1968, undated (Box 32, Folder 22)
    - GI Press, 1967-1969 (Box 32, Folder 23)
    - GI Press, 1970-1971 (Box 32, Folder 24)
    - GI Press, 1972-1973, undated (Box 32, Folder 25)
    - GI and Veteran Protests, 1967-1974, undated (Box 33, Folder 1)